chapter 14 of Black Beauty this LibriVox recording is in the public domain Black
Beauty by Anna suul chapter 14 James Howard Early one morning in December
John had just led me into my box after my daily exercise, and was strapping my
cloth on and James was coming in from the corn chamber with some oats, when the
master came into the stable. He looked rather serious, and held an open letter
in his hand. John fastened the door of my box, touched his cap, and waited for
orders good morning John,” said the master.
“I want to know if you have any complaints to make of
James.” “Complaint, sir? No, sir.” “Is he industrious at his work and respectful
to you?” “Yes, sir, always.” “You never find he slights his
work when your back is turned?” “Never, sir.” “That's well; but I must put another question.
Have you no reason to suspect, when he goes out with the horses to exercise
them or to take a message, that he stops about talking to his acquaintances, or
goes into houses where he has no business, leaving the horses
outside?” “No, sir, certainly not; and if anybody has been saying that about James,
I don't believe it, and I don't mean to believe it unless I have it fairly
proved before witnesses; it's not for me to say who has been trying to take away
James's character, but I will say this, sir, that a steadier, pleasanter honest
smarter young fellow I never had in this stable. I can trust his word and I can
trust his work; he is gentle and clever with the horses, and I would rather have
them in charge with him than with half the young fellas I know of in laced hats
and liveries; and whoever wants a character of James Howard,” said John, with
a decided jerk of his head, “let them come to John Manley The master stood all this time
grave and attentive, but as Jon finished his speech a broad smile spread over his
face, and looking kindly across at James, who all this time had stood still at the
door, he said, “James, my lad, set down the oats and come here I'm very glad to find
that JK's opinion of your character agrees so exactly with my own. John is a
cautious man,” he said, with a droll smile, “and it is not always easy to get his
opinion about people, so I thought if I beat the bush on this side the birds
would fly out, and I should learn what I wanted to know quickly;
so now we will come to business. I have a letter for my brother-in-law, Sir
Clifford Williams, of Clifford Hall. He wants me to find him a trustworthy young
groom, about 20 or 21 who knows his business. His old coachman, who has lived
with him 30 years, is getting feeble, and he wants a man to work with him and get
into his ways, who would be able, when the old man was pensioned off, to step into
his place. He would have 18 shillings a week at first, a stable suit, a driving
suit, a bedroom over the coach house and a boy under him. Sir Clifford is a good
master, and if you could get the place it would be a good start for you. I don't
want to part with you, and if you left us I know Jon would lose his right
hand.” “That I should, sir,” said John, “but I would not stand in his light for all the
world.” “How old are you, James?” said master 19 next May,
sir.” “That's young; what do you think, John?” “Well, sir, it is young; but he is as steady
as a man, and is strong, and well- grown, and though he has not had much
experience in driving, he has a light firm hand and a quick eye, and he is very
careful, and I'm quite sure no horse of his will be ruined for want of leaving
his feet and shoes looked after.” “Your word will go the furthest,
John,” said the master, “for Sir Clifford adds in a postcript If I could find a
man trained by your John I should like him better than any other;' so, James, lad,
think it over, talk to your mother at dinner time and then let me know what you
wish.” In a few days after this conversation it was fully settled that
James should go to Clifford Hall, in a month or 6 weeks, as it suited his master,
and in the meantime he was to get all the practice and driving that could be
given to him. I never knew the carriage to go out so often before; when the
mistress did not go out the master drove himself in the two whe Chase but now now,
whether it was the master or the young ladies, or only an errand, Ginger and I
were put in the carriage and James drove us. At the first John rode with him on
the box, telling him this and that, and after that James drove
alone. Then it was wonderful what a number of places the master would go to
in the city on Saturday, and what queer streets we were driven through. He was
sure to go to the railway station just as the train was coming in, and cabs and
carriages, carts and omnibuses were all trying to get over the bridge
together; that bridge wanted good horses and good drivers when the railway bell
was ringing, for it was narrow, and there was a very sharp turn up to the station,
where it would not have been at all difficult for people to run into each
other, if they did not look sharp and keep their wits about them end of chapter 14